welcome back to another video editing
欢迎回到另一个视频编辑
tutorial using the free software
使用免费软件的教程
kdenlive
克登利夫
in this video I'm just going to go
在这段视频中 我要去
through and demonstrate some of the
通过并演示一些
artistic video effects that you can
艺术视频效果 您可以
apply to video footage or to images so
应用于视频片段或图像 因此
to get started I'm just going to open a
作为开始 我只需要打开一个
couple clips we're going to do this one
几个片段 我们要做这一段
of the cyclists here and we're also
这里的自行车手 我们也
going to just do a regular image so
我要做一个普通的图像 所以
we'll do and I'll just drag and drop
我们会做的 我只会拖放
that one and I think it's under my
那个 我想它在我的
pictures yes we'll do this image here
图片 是的 我们将在这里制作这张图片
with the fish okay great so I'm just
鱼很好 所以我只是
gonna drag in first of all my video
我会先把我的视频拖进来
footage here and then drag in this image
请点击此处 然后拖入此图像
which will just come in by default
默认情况下 它将直接进入
before it'll play for 5 seconds this
在它播放5秒之前
video will and then it'll just go be the
视频将会 然后它就会成为
end of the video so I can zoom in on my
视频的结尾 这样我就可以放大我的
timeline to have a better view here or I
时间表以获得更好的这里或我的视野
can just click this button here if we
只需点击此处的按钮即可
hover over hover over it it says fit to
悬停在它认为适合它的上方
zoom to project now just kind of zoom it
立即缩放到项目只需将其缩放即可
so we can kind of see our project nice
所以我们可以把我们的项目看得很好
like that and then what I want to do is
像这样 然后我想要做的是
get to the effects so we've got
去看效果 这样我们就能
transitions tab down here we have
过渡选项卡在这里 我们有
effects you might need to click here
效果您可能需要单击此处
yours might be over in a different
你的可能会在不同的地方结束
location but regardless which want to go
地点 但不管你想去哪
into effects and then bring down this
使之生效 然后把这个
tab for artistic click that little
艺术标签点击那个小按钮
triangle to the side of artistic and it
三角形到艺术的边上 它
brings down all these different options
带来了所有这些不同的选择
we can also just type in and search like
我们也可以只输入并搜索如下内容
this dust if we want to find dust we
这些尘埃如果我们想要找到尘埃
just type in dust and it'll bring up
只需键入灰尘 它就会显示
just that one so we can search through
就那一个 这样我们就可以搜索了
for any effect by just using the search
任何效果 只需使用搜索
bar so let's just let's just start we
酒吧 所以让我们开始吧
have this three level threshold the best
有这三级门槛最好吗？
thing you can do is just just test all
您所能做的就是测试所有
these so we can left click and drag and
这样我们就可以左键单击并拖动
drop it over top of the video footage
把它放在视频片段的顶部
and we see what it does and then we have
我们看到了它的作用 然后我们就有了
options for it over here with this one
它的选项在这里 和这个一起
there's not a whole lot of options we
我们没有太多的选择
can disable it basically or enable it
基本上可以禁用它或启用它
but that's about it
但仅此而已
we have this one here binarize so this
我们这里有一个二进制的 所以这个
turns everything binary based on the
将所有内容都转换为基于
cover of the pixel so we can have to
覆盖像素 这样我们就可以
turn it basically black and white based
让它基本上以黑白为基础
off of the lightness of the pixel so
从像素的亮度来看
it's kind of cool I'm going to delete it
挺酷的 我要把它删除了
another way we can add the effects to is
我们可以添加效果的另一种方法是
just going down to the video clip in the
我只想看一下
timeline and right click and go to add
时间轴 然后单击鼠标右键并转至添加
effect and then we can just go
效果 然后我们就可以走了
which everyone we want and right now
这是我们现在想要的每个人
we're doing artistic so we can go to
我们在做艺术表演 这样我们就可以去
artistic and do this next one let's just
艺术性的 然后做下一个 让我们
try cartoon and it creates kind of a
试试看卡通 它创造了一种
cartoony look and again we have options
卡通的样子 我们又一次有选择
for how we want to adjust this here so
对于我们想要如何在这里进行调整
we can kind of adjust it and make it
我们可以对它进行调整 让它
look a little bit different depending on
看起来有点不同 具体取决于
how we adjust up here I'll do this
我们如何调整这里 我来做这个
charcoal will drag and drop into here
木炭会拖放到这里
that's what charcoal looks like now I'm
这就是木炭现在的样子
going to move forward on my playhead to
我将在我的游戏头上前进到
this picture so we can apply this next
这张图片 这样我们就可以在下一步应用
one
一
dither we'll apply it to this picture
抖动 我们将把它应用于这张图片
here and again we have different levels
一次又一次我们有不同的水平
or different adjustments we can make to
或者我们可以做出不同的调整
change the way the effect looks on this
更改效果在此上的外观
picture we can apply multiple to if you
图片我们可以应用多个 如果您
want to do this dither and the dust at
想要做这个抖动和尘埃在
the same time we just apply it over top
同时我们只是把它涂在上面
and then it changes that one we couldn't
然后它改变了我们做不到的那个
really tell but if we did like this
真的很清楚 但如果我们像这样
binary that we did earlier it'll make it
我们之前做的二进制代码 它会成功的
look really extreme different I'm gonna
看起来真的很不一样 我要
delete both these so to delete the
同时删除这两项 以便删除
effect I'm just going up and clicking on
效果我只是上前点击一下
this red garbage can and the top right
这个红色垃圾桶和右上角
of the kind of the project window or the
项目窗口的类型或
settings window for the properties what
属性的设置窗口是什么
else we got emboss but the cool thing is
否则我们就有浮雕了 但最酷的是
though I should show you two so it's
虽然我应该给你们看两个所以这是
applying it to the video it might take a
将其应用于视频可能需要
little bit of time to process but
需要一点时间来处理 但是
actually we can play the video that's
实际上 我们可以播放这段视频
kind of the cool thing about these
这些东西的酷之处在于
effects is that it applies it to the
效果是它将其应用于
whole video which is pretty cool like
整个视频很酷 就像
this one we have old film so it's gonna
这一部我们有旧胶卷 所以它会
make it look like an old film and I
让它看起来像一部老电影 我
think that shakes a little bit and
我觉得这有点动摇了
flashes maybe yeah so that's how it does
闪光 也许是的 所以就是这样
that and we can combine old film with
这样我们就可以把旧胶片和
grain I think and also with there's this
谷物 我想 还有这个
one vignette vignette vignette dad you
一个小插曲爸爸你
say this word and then we can also do
说这个词 然后我们也可以做
there's an alliance of-- somewhere I was
有一个联盟--我在某个地方
doing I have scratch lines so with all
我对所有人都有底线吗？
these together it'll create a really
这些加在一起就会创造出一个真正的
interesting look for like old film so we
像老电影一样有趣的样子 所以我们
have two lines these vertical lines
有两条线这些垂直线
appearing we have like a yeah
看起来我们有一个是的
anyway I I just want to show that you
不管怎么说 我只是想让你知道
can apply multiple effects over top of
可以在顶部应用多个效果
each other to create kind of a cool
彼此创造了一种酷炫的
looking thing and you notice it's kind
看着东西 你会注意到它很亲切
of going slow it's a little bit
放慢速度 这是有点
not up to full speed that's cuz its
不是全速 那是因为它
processing all of these effects when we
当我们处理所有这些影响时
actually render it out I'm gonna click
实际上呈现出来 我要点击
render and choose a place to save on our
渲染并选择要保存在我们的
computer it won't be like that it'll be
电脑 不会是那样的 会是那样的
just a normal nice smooth video so yeah
只是一个普通的、流畅的视频 所以是的
I'm not gonna show any more of those but
我不会再展示这些了 但是
that's basically it go through and play
这基本上就是它通过并播放
with all these and get familiar with how
所有这些 并熟悉如何
they work because yeah they provide some
它们起作用是因为它们提供了一些
pretty cool they can provide some pretty
很酷 他们可以提供一些漂亮的
cool effects on your video and pictures
视频和图片上的炫酷效果
that you're using in Caden life
你在卡登生活中使用的
hopefully you found this video
希望你找到了这段视频
informative go ahead and like and
信息量大 继续 点赞
subscribe comment below I'd love to hear
订阅下面的评论我很乐意听到
your feedback and I'll catch you on the
你的反馈 我会及时通知你的
next video
下一个视频